SAI SANDEEP NANGINENI

sai.nangineni@gmail.com

+1 510 807 9485

Linkedin

Github

PROFILE SUMMARY

Proficient and talented in problem solving, with good written and verbal communication, analytics, coding, motivated and has a vision. Talented, innovative, and enthusiastic about learning emerging technologies, and solve complex problems. Professional experience in application development. Good knowledge of workflows, object-oriented design and SDLC(Software Development Life Cycle).

EDUCATION

Master's in Computer Science

(August 2021 - Present)

California State University East Bay (CSUEB), California, United States

Coursework: Data Structures, Database Management Systems, Operating Systems, Advanced Computer Networks, Full Stack Development, Advanced Algorithms.

Bachelors in Computer Science Engineering

(August 2017 - August 2021)

Gokaraju Rangaraju Institute of Engineering and Technology, India

Coursework: Data Structures, Database Management Systems(DBMS), Object-Oriented Design(OOD).

EXPERIENCE

• Gayatri Projects Private Limited | Software Engineer Intern

(January 2020 - August 2021)

- Worked on Agile methodology including team-based design and code reviews.
- Implementation of MVC architecture by separating the Business Logic from the presentation Logic using the Struts framework.
- Worked on **XML** for transferring and retrieving data between different applications.
- Worked in using AngularJS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, Animations, and Flux concepts.
- Developed the User Interactive web pages in a professional manner using web technologies like HTML, CSS, XHTML, and jQuery, based on ADA standards.
- Interacted with java controllers (**JQUERY**, **Ajax**, and **JSON** to write/read data from back-end systems).
- Used **SVN** for version control and **QC** for defect tracking.
- Worked on the existing code into **JSP** by using core **JSTL**.
- Worked with Cassandra Node Connector for database persistence to interact with Cassandra NoSQL
 DB with Spring Data to unify and ease the access to Cassandra persistence stores.
- Prepared JUnit test cases using Mockito and PowerMockito and executed the test cases using JUnit.
- Used **Eclipse** as **IDE** for the development of the application and **SVN** for the code repository.
- Experienced **GIT** for maintaining source code.

• Ingwa Labs | Web Developer Intern

(September 2018 - December 2019)

- To analyze the requirements and develop enhancements that will mostly benefit users.
- Modified the existing website by adding suitable naming conventions and coding standards.
- Worked with user interfaces and applied usability principles to portals.
- My primary role was to improve **GUI**, solve navigational issues and provide support to the senior web developers.
- Used Wireframes to draw the user requirements.
- Developed **UI** using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript** validations and **XML**.
- Developed clickable prototypes using HTML, DHTML, Photoshop, CSS and JavaScript.
- Involved in writing application-level code to interact with APIs, and Web Services using AJAX, JSON and XML.
- Provided maintenance to several websites.
- Responsible for code optimization and testing of the website across different browsers.
- In addition to code development, maintained project documentation and assisted in application design.
- Created and maintained the layout and look and feel of each portal with CSS.
- Handled PHP backend development for a dynamic database-driven website
- Used JavaScript, CSS, and HTML to create front-end screens of the module
- Tested websites and fixing any existing bugs using Firebug.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, C++, C#, Java, Python, C
- Frameworks: .NET, VueJS, React Native, Spring Boot, Bootstrap, Mocha, Chai
- Relational Databases and Non-Relational Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, DynamoDB
- Tools: IntelliJ, Postman, NPM, Git, Github, AWS, Google Maps Platform, Jenkins, Android Studio
- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Rest APIs, AngularJS, Typescript
- Platforms: Linux, Windows, Mac
- Interests: Automation, Web development, Micro Services

PROJECTS

• Farmers Club Web Application | Reactjs, Express.js, Node.js

- Designed and developed a Web application for a farming club using MERN (MongoDB, Express JS, ReactJS, Node JS) to display the statistical growth in the crop yield and buy their franchised apparel.
- Implemented Role-Based Authentication to provide different UI for different roles (mem/non-mem/admin).
- Backend unit Testing scripts are scripted in Mocha with chai assertions and executed.

Distance Matrix Routing Application | Reactjs, Google Maps Platform

- Worked independently on a website for delivery drivers to reach multiple destinations in minimal time.
- Used TomTom map SDK to get the real-time traffic on roads to give the best route.
- The default route was calculated for the cars. Can be calculated for other modes of transport as well.

• Cryptocurrency Dashboard | Reactjs, React Hooks, Rest API

- Developed a dashboard to display the price of Crypto Currency in real-time.
- Real-time prices are retrieved from coingecko.com with the help of open-source Rest API.
- Price updates of the digital currencies are executed with react hooks.

• Serverless URL Shortener | AWS, JAVA, API gateways, DynamoDB

- Designed a static HTML webpage and implemented a Serverless URL Shortener.
- o GET, POST methods were used to redirect the short URL and to store the token value.
- DynamoDB was used to store the short and destination URLs.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Back End Development and APIs (FreeCodeCamp) | NodeJS, MongoDB

(Sep 16, 2022)

- Completed around 300 hours of coursework by freeCodeCamp. Click here.
- Database Design and Database Programming (Oracle)

(June 29, 2019)

o Completed an examination on Database Design and Database Programming by Oracle academy.

Here is my portfolio showing my interests and the projects I have worked on. Please have a look.